# Jessé Souza Cavalcanti Neto

Software Developer
jessecavalcanti20@gmail.com
linkedin
Github
Personal Site

## Personal Statement

Working professionaly as a Software Developer since 2018, i had a chance to work with web and with system development as well, using python, Java, and Web, but always in search of learning new technologies and increasing my skills as a professional developer.

# Working Experience

### Research and Software Developer Trainee

at Virtus

December 2019 - Present

Virtus is a Research, Development and Innovation Center in Information Technology, Communication and Automation associated with CEEI / UFCG.

- Worked in the development of web systems using Angular and Springboot technologies
- Worked in development of systems using Python and Java
- Had the opportunity to work with several development teams on different projects, which helped me to adapt more quickly

### **Core Team**

at OpendevUFCG

November 2019 - Present

Opendev UFCG is an organization formed by students from the Federal University of Campina Grande that aims to empower students and spread open source culture.

- Act as Maintainer of some of the organization's repositories, including a data registration and distribution system and the organization's website
- Acted as organizer of the Hacktoberfest 2020 event, working both in the development of the website and in the presentation of the event.

### **Frontend Developer**

at Embedded Lab. UFCG

October 2018 - April 2019

Embedded is part of the Center for Electrical and Computer Engineering (CEEI) at the Federal University of Campina Grande (UFCG)

- Worked on the development of a web system for the construction of Bayesian networks using the AngularJS framework and graphic libraries such as D3.js
- Had the opportunity to act as Scrum Master for a few sprints, which helped me to develop soft skills related to working with people and using versioning using Git

# Languages

English - Intermediary Portuguese - Advanced

# **Education**

### **Bootcamp Ignite Rocketseat**

ReactJS March 2021 - Present

### Federal University Of Campina Grande

Undergraduate on Science Computing January 2017 - Present